Miscellany
Marist Archives and Special Collections
Miscellany
2.3.11
Marist College
MMM
MMM
MMM
  Box 1642
- Miscellany, 2.3.11
  - Charcoal sketch of Lowell Thomas by McClelland Barclay; verso: "To Mr. Barclay who played on LT's '9 Olden Men' team. L.T. should have been a mining engineer"; lithograph print, undated; 1; 14 x 10 b&w (Box 1642)
  - Verso: To Mr Barclay who played on LT's "9 Old Men" team L.T. should have been a mining engineer., 1-verso (Box 1642)
  - Charcoal sketch of Lowell Thomas by McClelland Barclay; inscription: "to my old John T. Reynolds, a stout heated chap who is bound to make a go of anything he tackles. From his admirer, Lowell Thomas"; lithograph print, undated; 2; 14 x 10 b&w (Box 1642)
  - Charcoal sketch of Lowell Thomas by McClelland Barclay [lithograph print], [105 copies], undated; 3; 14 x 10 b&w (Box 1642)
  - Sketch of Lowell Thomas by Rudolph [?]; lithograph print, undated; 4; 12 1/2 x 10 b&w (Box 1642)
  - "First Aerial Crossing of the Pacific on Man's First Flight Around the World"; lithograph print [18 copies], undated; 5; 11 x 15 color (Box 1642)
  - Engraving of Henry Irving with caption, from photograph by Warwick Brookes, Manchester, undated; 6; 9 x 7 b&w (Box 1642)
  - Man dressed in uniform; lithograph print, undated; 7; 7 1/2 x 4 color (Box 1642)
  - "Hay Makers"; engraved by W. Ward; lithograph print, 1923 March 24; 8; 9 1/2 x 14 color (Box 1642)
  - "Zooeven verschenen: De Eerste Vlucht om de Wereld: Prijs f 5,-, gebonden f 6,50 Alhier Verkrijgbaar"; lithograph print [3 copies], undated; 9; 14 1/2 x 9 color (Box 1642)
  - "Zooeven verschenen: De Eerste Vlucht om de Wereld: Prijs f 5,-, gebonden f 6,50 Alhier Verkrijgbaar"; lithograph print, undated; 10; 14 1/2 x 9 color (Box 1642)
  - Sketch of rose window of the Cathedral of Notre Dame; lithograph print, undated; 11; 12 x 17 b&w (Box 1642)
  - Linoleum print of T. E. Lawrence by Grosvenor, 1974 February; 12; 17 1/2 x 11 b&w (Box 1642)
  - "The Timid Soul"; cartoon; lithograph print, 1941 November 10; 13; 17 1/2 x 13 b&w (Box 1642)
  Box 1643
- Miscellany, 2.3.11
  - "Picking Up The Reigns" by frank J. Hopper; inscription: "With warm personal regards to Lowell Thomas, [signed] Frank Hopper; lithograph print, 1981; 1; 14 1/2 x 19 color (Box 1643)
  - Ink drawing by K. Wiese used as illustration for "The Wreck of the Dumaru" by Lowell Thomas, page 37, circa 1930; 2; 8 1/2 x 5 1/2 b&w (Box 1643)
  - Verso: Page 37: There was a perfect hell in the fire room, cursing, fights., 2-verso (Box 1643)
  - Ink drawing by K. Wiese used as illustration for "The Wreck of the Dumaru" by Lowell Thomas, page 56, circa 1930; 3; 8 1/2 x 5 1/2 b&w (Box 1643)
  - Verso: Page 56:, the stern of the Dunnarn[?] towered high above us, 3-verso (Box 1643)
  - Ink drawing by K. Wiese used as illustration for "The Wreck of the Dumaru" by Lowell Thomas, page 77, circa 1930; 4; 8 1/2 x 5 1/2 b&w (Box 1643)
  - Verso: 77 - -we continued to row among the boxes and other wreakage, 4-verso (Box 1643)
  - Ink drawing by K. Wiese used as illustration for "The Wreck of the Dumaru" by Lowell Thomas, page 102, circa 1930; 5; 8 1/2 x 5 1/2 b&w (Box 1643)
  - Verso: Page 102: _, and he stood there, and then he sagged and was Kneeling there., 5-verso (Box 1643)
  - Ink drawing by K. Wiese used as illustration for "The Wreck of the Dumaru" by Lowell Thomas, page 121, circa 1930; 6; 8 1/2 x 5 1/2 b&w (Box 1643)
  - Page 121 - The water was now knee deep, 6-verso (Box 1643)
  - Ink drawing by K. Wiese used as illustration for "The Wreck of the Dumaru" by Lowell Thomas, page 135, circa 1930; 7; 8 1/2 x 5 1/2 b&w (Box 1643)
  - Page 135 - The next leg of the journey brought us to a river, 7-verso (Box 1643)
  - Ink drawing by Charles [..] possibly used as illustration for "The Wreck of the Dumaru" by Lowell Thomas; inscription: "To Mr. and Mrs. Lowell Thomas with regards; lithograph print, 1931; 8; 10 1/2 x 7 1/2 b&w (Box 1643)
  - Ink drawing by Charles [..] possibly used as illustration for "The Wreck of the Dumaru" by Lowell Thomas; inscription: "To Mr. and Mrs. Lowell Thomas with regards; lithograph print, 1933; 9; 10 1/2 x 7 1/2 b&w (Box 1643)
  - Watercolor painting of a building; verso: Presented to Mr. Lowell Thomas, Yours Sincerely B. [?], undated; 10; 10 x 14 color (Box 1643)
  - Verso: Presented to Ms.[?] Lowell Thomas, Yours Sincerely [unknown signature], 10-verso (Box 1643)
  - Watercolor painting of a tower, undated; 11; 13 1/2 x 8 1/2 color (Box 1643)
  - "Sir John Gage" by Hans Holbein; lithograph print, undated; 12; 16 x 12 color (Box 1643)
  - Watercolor illustration signed "Constantinople, 1920" in lower right corner, 13; 10 1/2 x 7 1/2 color (Box 1643)
  - Watercolor illustration signed "Constantinople, 1920" in lower right corner, 14; 10 1/2 x 7 1/2 color (Box 1643)
  - Watercolor illustration signed "Constantinople, 1920" in lower right corner, 15; 10 1/2 x 7 1/2 color (Box 1643)
  - Watercolor illustration signed "Constantinople, 1920" in lower right corner, 16; 10 1/2 x 7 1/2 color (Box 1643)
  - Watercolor illustration signed "Constantinople, 1920" in lower right corner, 17; 10 1/2 x 7 1/2 color (Box 1643)
  - Watercolor illustration signed "Constantinople, 1920" in lower right corner, 18; 10 1/2 x 7 1/2 color (Box 1643)
  - Watercolor illustration signed "Constantinople, 1920" in lower right corner, 19; 10 1/2 x 7 1/2 color (Box 1643)
  - Poster titled "Oasis on the Path to Mecca", undated; 20; 20 x 16 color (Box 1643)
  - Poster titled "Oasis on the Path to Mecca", undated; 21; 20 x 16 color (Box 1643)
  - Poster titled "For your evening news: Lowell Thomas, Now 7:15 P.M., Don Lee-Mutual"; lithograph, undated; 22; 18 x 24 color (Box 1643)
  - Poster titled "Going Places with Lowell Thomas"; lithograph, undated; 23; 41 x 27 color (Box 1643)
  - Poster titled "Raiders of the Deep by Lowell Thomas"; lithograph, circa 1928; 24; 29 x 20 color (Box 1643)
  - Window card promoting "The Biggest Scoop of the Season: See the World as it is today. Travel 97,000 miles in a Flight around the World with Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas Jr. An All Color Pictorial Epic and a Never to be Forgotten Experience" lithograph poster, 1947 March 30; 25; 10 1/2 x 28 b&w (Box 1643)
  - Photograph of unidentified woman, undated; 26; 8 x 6 b&w (Box 1643)
  - Photograph of unidentified woman; inscription: To Frances - With sincere admiration, From - Zetta, undated; 27; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1643)
  Box 1644
- Miscellany, 2.3.11
  - Banana plantation, Jamaica [very fragile] [photograph], 1895; 1; 7 x 9 1/2 b&w (Box 1644)
  - 1982 calendar; includes photograph of Cripple Creek, Colorado, 2; 12 x 15 1/2 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Caricature of Lowell Thomas [photograph], undated; 3; 13 1/2 x 7 1/2 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Caricature of Lowell Thomas [photograph], undated; 4; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Dinner: "Trans-Atlantic Flyers Testimonial Dinner To Dr. James N. Kimball - Hotel Roosevelt - April 9, 1931; Amelia Earhart, fourth from right (back row); Lowell Thomas, seventh from right (back row) [photograph], 1931 April 9; 5; 15 x 18 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Dinner: "Movietonews Dinner Tendered to Laurence Stallings' Expedition - New York Athletic Club - Jan. 17, 1935"; Lowell Thomas seated third from right at rear table [photograph], 1935 January 17; 6; 19 x 11 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Dinner: "The Explorers Club"; Vilhjalmur Stefansson seated fourth from left; Lowell Thomas, fifth from left; Matthew Henson seated at right [photograph], circa 1930s; 7; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Dinner: "10th Annual Dinner, Chicago Press Veterans Assn. - December 4, 1948 - LaSalle Hotel - Chicago, Illinois [photograph], 1948 December 4; 8; 20 x 12 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Greenville, Ohio; billboard proclaiming "Birthplace of Lowell Thomas at Woodington" [photograph], undated; 9; 12 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (New Guinea) [photograph], 1957; 10; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (New Guinea) [photograph], 1957; 11; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (New Guinea) [photograph], 1957; 12; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (Timbuktu to Mozambique and on to Madagascar) [photograph], 1958; 13; 12 1/2 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (Timbuktu to Mozambique and on to Madagascar) [photograph], 1958; 14; 12 1/2 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - George and Agnes McGrath with Lowell Thomas [photograph], circa 1960s; 15; 15 x 16 color (Box 1644)
  - Nepal: Coronation of King Mahendra [photograph], 1956; 16; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Verso: King Mahendra Bir Bikram Shah Diva and his queen folowing the coronation, 16-verso (Box 1644)
  - Nepal: Coronation of King Mahendra [photograph], 1956; 17; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Verso: Wedding King of Nepal; In center Chris Young[?], 17-verso (Box 1644)
  - Nepal: Coronation of King Mahendra [photograph], 1956; 18; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Nepal: Coronation of King Mahendra [photograph], 1956; 19; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Verso: Nepalese King Mahenra and Queen on royal elephant. LT in Tophat and striped pants rode an elephant in the same procession. 1955, 19-verso (Box 1644)
  - Cathedral of Notre Dame (exterior view) [photograph], undated; 20; 12 x 15 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Cathedral of Notre Dame (interior view) [photograph], undated; 21; 10 x 13 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Cathedral of Notre Dame (interior view) [photograph], undated; 22; 10 x 13 b&w (Box 1644)
  - President Woodrow Wilson shaking the hand of former President William Howard Taft [photograph], undated; 23; 17 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Christl Thalhammer and Lowell Thomas [photograph], circa 1963; 24; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Christl Thalhammer, at right, and Lowell Thomas [photograph], circa 1963; 25; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - University of Nebraska award ceremony for Lowell Thomas [photograph], undated; 26; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Verso: [semi-legible], 26-verso (Box 1644)
  - University of Nebraska award ceremony for Lowell Thomas [photograph], undated; 27; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - University of Nebraska award ceremony for Lowell Thomas [photograph], undated; 28; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Verso: dean Mud[?] College Nebraska; J. Smith, 28-verso (Box 1644)
  - World War II: Lowell Thomas sitting in cockpit of airplane talks to unidentified military officer [photograph], circa 1940s; 29; 10 1/2 x 10 1/2 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Verso: LT WWII; Col ?, 29-verso (Box 1644)
  - World War II: Lowell Thomas in conversation with unidentified military personnel [photograph], circa 1940s; 30; 10 1/2 x 10 1/2 b&w (Box 1644)
  - World War II: B-29 airplane; inscription: "To Lowell Thomas whose "Sunny" along with my Bob and others like them, we build for today and tomorrow, [signed] [?] Schaefer" [photograph], 1944 September 29; 31; 15 x 20 b&w (Box 1644)
  - World War II: B-29 airplane; inscription: "To'Sunny' Thomas with best wishes and to remind you that you started to grow on a PT, [signed] [?] Schaefer" [photograph], 1944 September 30; 32; 15 x 20 b&w (Box 1644)
  - British biplane fighter in flight [photograph], undated; 33; 14 x 18 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Verso: A cloudy day; Bristol fighter in flight, 33-verso (Box 1644)
  - Unidentified award ceremony for Lowell Thomas (related to skiing) [photograph], circa 1970; 34; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Unidentified award ceremony for Lowell Thomas (related to skiing) [photograph], circa 1970; 35; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Unidentified award ceremony for Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr. [photograph], circa 1970; 36; 8 x 10 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Unidentified award ceremony for Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr. [photograph], circa 1970; 37; 8 x 10 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Unidentified award ceremony for Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr. [photograph], circa 1970; 38; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Unidentified award ceremony for Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr. [photograph], circa 1970; 39; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Unidentified award ceremony for Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr. [photograph], circa 1970; 40; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Unidentified award ceremony for Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr. [photograph], circa 1970; 41; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  - Unidentified award ceremony for Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr. [photograph], circa 1970; 42; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1644)
  Box 1645
- Miscellany, 2.3.11
  - Note: "Pictures made for the Hammersley Hill booklet made for sale purposes" [applies to photographs 2-13], circa 1970s; 1; 10 1/2 x 8 b&w (Box 1645)
  - "Pictures made for the Hammersley Hill booklet made for sale purposes", circa 1970s; 2; 7 1/2 x 6 color (Box 1645)
  - "Pictures made for the Hammersley Hill booklet made for sale purposes", circa 1970s; 3; 5 x 5 color (Box 1645)
  - "Pictures made for the Hammersley Hill booklet made for sale purposes", circa 1970s; 4; 5 x 4 color (Box 1645)
  - "Pictures made for the Hammersley Hill booklet made for sale purposes", circa 1970s; 5; 3 1/2 x 3 1/2 color (Box 1645)
  - "Pictures made for the Hammersley Hill booklet made for sale purposes", circa 1970s; 6; 8 x 6 color (Box 1645)
  - "Pictures made for the Hammersley Hill booklet made for sale purposes", circa 1970s; 7; 12 1/2 x 10 1/2 color (Box 1645)
  - "Pictures made for the Hammersley Hill booklet made for sale purposes", circa 1970s; 8; 11 1/2 x 10 1/2 color (Box 1645)
  - "Pictures made for the Hammersley Hill booklet made for sale purposes", circa 1970s; 9; 11 1/2 x 10 color (Box 1645)
  - "Pictures made for the Hammersley Hill booklet made for sale purposes", circa 1970s; 10; 11 1/2 x 11 color (Box 1645)
  - "Pictures made for the Hammersley Hill booklet made for sale purposes", circa 1970s; 11; 12 x 10 1/2 color (Box 1645)
  - "Pictures made for the Hammersley Hill booklet made for sale purposes", circa 1970s; 12; 11 1/2 x 10 color (Box 1645)
  - "Pictures made for the Hammersley Hill booklet made for sale purposes", circa 1970s; 13; 11 1/2 x 10 color (Box 1645)
  - Exterior view of house at Quaker Hill; signed by B. Lynn Sumner [photograph], circa 1930s; 14; 20 x 16 b&w (Box 1645)
  - A close up of the porch of house at Quaker Hill [photograph], circa 1930s; 15; 18 x 16 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Interior room of house at Quaker Hill [photograph], circa 1930s; 16; 16 x 18 1/2 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Interior room of house at Quaker Hill [photograph], circa 1930s; 17; 18 x 16 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Exterior view of house at Quaker Hill [photograph], circa 1930s; 18; 10 x 12 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Exterior view of house at Quaker Hill [photograph], circa 1930s; 19; 10 x 12 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Lowell Thomas home [photograph], 1931; 20; 10 1/2 x 13 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Verso: Landscape Architect Mr. Tufts, owner Lowell Thomas, location of job Quaker [?], Pawling, NY, Date completed spring 1931], 20-verso (Box 1645)
  - Mizzen Top Hotel at Quaker Hill [photograph], undated; 21; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Lowell Thomas Collection - Mizzen Top Hotel, 21-verso (Box 1645)
  - T. E. Lawrence sitting on a bicycle [photograph], circa 1930; 22; 20 x 24 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Four photographs glued onto poster board; clockwise from top left: Gene Tunney and Lowell Thomas; Lowell Thomas; Heywood Broun; softball game, circa 1930s; 23; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Four photographs possibly depicting early days at Cripple Creek, Colorado glued onto poster board, undated; 24; 20 x 16 b&w (Box 1645)
  - "European Skyways" [photograph], circa 1928; 25; 25 x 20 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Verso: "To the Countess in remembrance of the first time we saw you on the aerodrome near Stutgart [signed] Lowell Thomas", 25-verso (Box 1645)
  - "European Skyways" [photograph], 1928 December 25; 26; 25 x 20 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Verso: "Merry Christmas to the Count from Lowell Thomas Jr., "Sonny", 26-verso (Box 1645)
  - Snow covered Antarctic mountains; person on a snowmobile carrying an American flag in foreground [photograph], undated; 27; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Snow covered Antarctic mountains; person on a snowmobile carrying an American flag in foreground [photograph], undated; 28; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Snowmobile with an American flag [photograph], undated; 29; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Setting up camp on the Antarctic mountains [photograph], undated; 30; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Verso: "The Lowell Thomas Mountains, in Antarctica. This Wisconsin Univ. expedition was the only one ever to reach them", 30-verso (Box 1645)
  - Setting up a tent on Antarctic terrain [photograph], undated; 31; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1645)
  - A person climbing the mountains of Antarctica [photograph], undated; 32; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1645)
  - A person standing on an Antarctic rock outcrop [photograph], undated; 33; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Close-up of rock and a rock hammer [photograph], undated; 34; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1645)
  - An open field of snow in Antarctica [photograph], undated; 35; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Ice flight over Antarctica [photograph], 1947 December 23; 36; 20 x 24 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Verso: "Neny Glacier, Marguerite Bay", 36-verso (Box 1645)
  - Ice flight over Antarctica [photograph], 1947 December 22; 37; 20 x 20 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Verso: "H. C. Petersen physicist, crevasse where 1 man went down 110 feet for 12 hours. Northeast Glacier, Neny Fiord, Palmer Land", 37-verso (Box 1645)
  - Ice flight over Antarctica [photograph], 1947 December 21; 38; 20 x 20 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Verso: "Mountainous plateau -Marguerite Bay, Palmer Land", 38-verso (Box 1645)
  - Ice flight over Antarctica [photograph], 1947 December 21; 39; 20 x 24 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Ice flight over Antarctica [photograph], 1947 December 3; 40; 20 x 20 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Verso: "George VI Sound, Alex Island", 40-verso (Box 1645)
  - Ice flight over Antarctica [photograph], 1947 November 27; 41; 20 x 20 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Verso: "Wintering base, Stonington Island, Palmer Land", 41-verso (Box 1645)
  - Ice flight over Antarctica" [photograph], 1947 December 21; 42; 20 x 24 b&w (Box 1645)
  - Verso: "Palmer Land, crevasse - some 100 feet across, 1000 feet deep, 1947", 42-verso (Box 1645)
  - Framed photograph of a sketch of Lowell Thomas, Jr. by Clint Bradley [item is currently located in the Marist College Special Collections Hanging Storage Area], undated; 43; 20 x 16 1/2 b&w (Box 1645)
  Box 1646
- Miscellany, 2.3.11
  - 11 prints for use in the "Illustrated Book about the Far East: China, Tibet, Mongolia, Korea, Japan, Formosa, Manchuria, Serbia, Philippines Islands" by Martha Sawyers and William Reusswig (introduction by Lowell Thomas); lithographs, 1961; 1; 35 x 22 1/2 color (Box 1646)
  - 11 prints for use in the "Illustrated Book about the Far East: China, Tibet, Mongolia, Korea, Japan, Formosa, Manchuria, Serbia, Philippines Islands" by Martha Sawyers and William Reusswig (introduction by Lowell Thomas); lithographs, 1961; 2; 35 x 22 1/2 color (Box 1646)
  - 11 prints for use in the "Illustrated Book about the Far East: China, Tibet, Mongolia, Korea, Japan, Formosa, Manchuria, Serbia, Philippines Islands" by Martha Sawyers and William Reusswig (introduction by Lowell Thomas); lithographs, 1961; 3; 35 x 22 1/2 color (Box 1646)
  - 11 prints for use in the "Illustrated Book about the Far East: China, Tibet, Mongolia, Korea, Japan, Formosa, Manchuria, Serbia, Philippines Islands" by Martha Sawyers and William Reusswig (introduction by Lowell Thomas); lithographs, 1961; 4; 35 x 22 1/2 color (Box 1646)
  - 11 prints for use in the "Illustrated Book about the Far East: China, Tibet, Mongolia, Korea, Japan, Formosa, Manchuria, Serbia, Philippines Islands" by Martha Sawyers and William Reusswig (introduction by Lowell Thomas); lithographs, 1961; 5; 35 x 22 1/2 color (Box 1646)
  - 11 prints for use in the "Illustrated Book about the Far East: China, Tibet, Mongolia, Korea, Japan, Formosa, Manchuria, Serbia, Philippines Islands" by Martha Sawyers and William Reusswig (introduction by Lowell Thomas); lithographs, 1961; 6; 35 x 22 1/2 color (Box 1646)
  - 11 prints for use in the "Illustrated Book about the Far East: China, Tibet, Mongolia, Korea, Japan, Formosa, Manchuria, Serbia, Philippines Islands" by Martha Sawyers and William Reusswig (introduction by Lowell Thomas); lithographs, 1961; 7; 35 x 22 1/2 color (Box 1646)
  - 11 prints for use in the "Illustrated Book about the Far East: China, Tibet, Mongolia, Korea, Japan, Formosa, Manchuria, Serbia, Philippines Islands" by Martha Sawyers and William Reusswig (introduction by Lowell Thomas); lithographs, 1961; 8; 35 x 22 1/2 color (Box 1646)
  - 11 prints for use in the "Illustrated Book about the Far East: China, Tibet, Mongolia, Korea, Japan, Formosa, Manchuria, Serbia, Philippines Islands" by Martha Sawyers and William Reusswig (introduction by Lowell Thomas); lithographs, 1961; 9; 35 x 22 1/2 color (Box 1646)
  - 11 prints for use in the "Illustrated Book about the Far East: China, Tibet, Mongolia, Korea, Japan, Formosa, Manchuria, Serbia, Philippines Islands" by Martha Sawyers and William Reusswig (introduction by Lowell Thomas); lithographs, 1961; 10; 35 x 22 1/2 color (Box 1646)
  - 11 prints for use in the "Illustrated Book about the Far East: China, Tibet, Mongolia, Korea, Japan, Formosa, Manchuria, Serbia, Philippines Islands" by Martha Sawyers and William Reusswig (introduction by Lowell Thomas); lithographs, 1961; 11; 35 x 22 1/2 color (Box 1646)
  - Illustrated map of China, possibly used in the "Illustrated Book about the Far East: China, Tibet, Mongolia, Korea, Japan, Formosa, Manchuria, Serbia, Philippines Islands" by Martha Sawyers and William Reusswig (introduction by Lowell Thomas); lithographs, 1961; 12; 15 x 24 color (Box 1646)
  - "A Tibetan refugee child in an Asian gesture expressive of profound respect, sincere gratitude and humble petition"; lithograph, 1963; 13; 30 1/2 x 15 1/2 color (Box 1646)